# CHASE JOHNSTON

EMAIL: CHASEJ@LIVE.COM | PHONE: 603-703-4749

GITHUB: https://github.com/johnstoc13 | LINKEDIN: www.linkedin.com/in/chase-johnston8

PORTFOLIO: https://johnstoc13.gihub.io/Updated-Portfolio/

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Website designer and multiple business owner with experience creating modern, responsive websites for small businesses and leading positive change for teenagers and young adults. Extensive experience in multitasking, teamwork, communication and problem solving in a fast paced learning environment as an air traffic controller. With my accomplishments in experience, efficiency, and teamwork, I have proven success repeatedly and look forward to using these skills in future endeavors.

## **APPLICATIONS**

#### **FLICK THE DECK**

Flick The Deck is a fun application that combines "luck of the draw" with a faster path to movie selection based on user-selected criteria. Application is the result of a highly dynamic and cooperative team effort. I was tasked with the front end design, ensuring mobile responsiveness using Foundation CSS.

TECH USED: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Foundation, external APIs, Animate.css

CODE: https://github.com/mwoodervin/Flick-the-Deck

DEPLOYED SITE: https://mwoodervin.github.io/Flick-the-Deck/

#### **WEATHER DASHBOARD**

Application designed to get the current weather for a selected city and the 5 day forecast. It also displays the users most recent search history and loads their latest search upon page refresh.

TECH USED: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Moment.js, Font Awesome, external API

CODE: https://github.com/johnstoc13/Weather-Dashboard

DEPLOYED SITE: https://johnstoc13.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/

#### **PASSWORD GENERATOR**

Random password generator based on user-selected criteria. Users can choose password length, and character criteria. Runs in the browser and is mobile responsive using Bootstrap CSS framework.

TECH USED: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript

 ${\tt CODE:}\ \underline{\tt https://github.com/johnstoc13/Password-Generator}$ 

DEPLOYED SITE: https://johnstoc13.github.io/Password-Generator/

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS & ABILITIES**

• HTML

CSS

Bootstrap

Foundation

Javascript

jQuery

• Moment.js

Animate.css

NodeJS

JSONAJAX

• Command Line

Multitasking

Communication

Teamwork

Problem Solving

Efficiency

• Responsive Design

• Leading Change

Professionalism

Training

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## OWNER – GRANITE STATE STUDIO, LLC BROOKLINE, NH – MAY 2020 - PRESENT

Owner and web designer responsible for creating fast, affordable, and responsive websites for small businesses. Oversee marketing, social media, and all other small business duties.

## BUSINESS MANAGER – CHANGEMAKER TEENS, LLC

#### **BROOKLINE, NH - JULY 2017-PRESENT**

Co-owner and Business Manager for Changemaker Teens dedicated to helping teens and young adults discover a life direction that will bring purpose and meaning to their adult lives. Recently negotiated enrollment into the Finger Lakes Area Community Endowment (FLACE) allowing us to operate as a 501c3 non-profit and ensure maximum potential to improve the lives of teens throughout their community and nationwide. Currently manage all website related tasks, graphic design, sales and marketing strategies, and financial analysis.

## CO-FOUNDER – J&J EVENT SERVICES, LLC

#### **BROOKLINE, NH - APRIL 2016 - JULY 2017**

Co-owner and creator of company specializing in cruise charter management. Successfully negotiated cruise charter contract with a major cruise line and our client. Negotiated multiple price reductions for cabins, ensuring maximum profit potential. Also secured reservations management contract, further saving our client thousands of dollars.

# AIR TRAFFIC CONTROLLER – FEDERAL AVIATION ADMINISTRATION NASHUA, NH – SEPTEMBER 2008-PRESENT

Radar controller responsible for the safe, orderly, and expeditious flow of traffic in some of the most congested and complicated airspace within the National Airspace System. My skills were recently showcased at a Senior Leadership Conference within the FAA as a demonstration of professionalism and safety. Certified On the Job Training Instructor responsible for training new hires. Also certified as Controller In Charge to run the operational area when assigned. Traffic Management Coordinator since 2018. Professional Standards Representative since 2017. High stress environment that allows for zero mistakes.

## **EDUCATION**

UNIVERSITY OF NEW HAMPSHIRE – CODING BOOTCAMP - 2020

MINNEAPOLIS COMMUNITY & TECHNICAL COLLEGE – A.A.S. AIR TRAFFIC CONTROL - 2007

METROPOLITAN STATE UNIVERSITY OF DENVER – B.S. AVIATION TECHNOLOGY - 2006